<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on b0x68</title><link>http://localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on b0x68</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>101.1: Determining and Configuring Hardware Settings</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/101-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/101-1/</guid><description>Tutorial: Determining and Configuring Hardware Settings for LPIC-1 Exam # Introduction # In this tutorial, we will cover how to determine and configure fundamental system hardware, an essential skill for the LPIC-1 exam. This includes enabling and disabling integrated peripherals, differentiating between mass storage devices, determining hardware resources, and using various tools to list and manipulate hardware information. By the end of this tutorial, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a strong grasp of the necessary commands and concepts.</description></item><item><title>101.2: Boot the System</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/101-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/101-2/</guid><description>LPIC-1 Exam Objective: 101.2 Boot the System # In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the essential aspects of booting a Linux system, aligned with the LPIC-1 exam objective 101.2. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore common commands, the boot sequence, and various init systems, as well as how to check boot events in log files.
Key Knowledge Areas # 1. Common Commands to the Boot Loader and Kernel Options at Boot Time # Boot Loader Commands # The boot loader is the first software that runs after the BIOS/UEFI initializes the hardware.</description></item><item><title>101.3: Change runlevels || boot targets and shutdown || reboot system</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/101-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/101-3/</guid><description>Managing Runlevels and Boot Targets with SysVinit and Systemd # In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the key aspects of changing runlevels, boot targets, shutting down, and rebooting a system for the LPIC-1 exam. We’ll explore both SysVinit and systemd, including setting default runlevels/boot targets, alerting users, and properly terminating processes.
1. Setting the Default Runlevel or Boot Target # SysVinit # SysVinit uses the /etc/inittab file to set the default runlevel.</description></item><item><title>102.1: Designing a Disk Partitioning Scheme for Linux</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/102-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/102-1/</guid><description>Designing a Disk Partitioning Scheme for Linux # Designing a disk partitioning scheme is a fundamental task when setting up a Linux system. It involves planning how to allocate different filesystems and swap space across various partitions or disks. This tutorial will guide you through the essential considerations and provide real-world examples to help you understand the process.
Key Concepts and Terminology # Before diving into the design process, let&amp;rsquo;s familiarize ourselves with some key concepts and terminology:</description></item><item><title>102.2: Installing and Configuring a Boot Manager</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/102-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/102-2/</guid><description>Installing and Configuring a Boot Manager: A Practical Guide for LPIC-1 Exam # Introduction # In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the essential steps to select, install, and configure a boot manager, a crucial skill for the LPIC-1 certification exam. We&amp;rsquo;ll focus on GRUB Legacy and GRUB 2, as these are the most commonly used boot loaders in Linux environments. By the end of this guide, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a solid understanding of how to manage boot loaders, provide alternative boot locations, and interact with the boot process.</description></item><item><title>102.3: Managing Shared Libraries</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/102-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/lpic/lpic1/objectives/102-3/</guid><description>Managing Shared Libraries in Linux: A Real-World Guide # Introduction # Managing shared libraries is a crucial skill for Linux system administrators, ensuring that executable programs have the necessary resources to function correctly. This tutorial will cover the LPIC-1 exam objective 102.3: Manage shared libraries. We will explore how to identify shared libraries, locate them, and load them, using practical examples to solidify your understanding.
Key Knowledge Areas # Identify shared libraries.</description></item><item><title>Creating a New Theme</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid><description>Introduction # This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description></item><item><title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid><description>Move static content to static # Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description></item><item><title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/goisforlovers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/goisforlovers/</guid><description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Hugo</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugoisforlovers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugoisforlovers/</guid><description>Step 1. Install Hugo # Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs # Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:</description></item></channel></rss>