<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SSH on b0x68</title>
    <link>http://b0x68.github.io/tags/ssh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SSH on b0x68</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 17:30:47 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://b0x68.github.io/tags/ssh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switch Users in Multiuser Environnment</title>
      <link>http://b0x68.github.io/techcontent/switch-users-in-multiuser-environnment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 17:30:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://b0x68.github.io/techcontent/switch-users-in-multiuser-environnment/</guid>
      <description>Red Hat Certified Systems Administrator Exam Objective: Log in and switch users in multiuser targets In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the crucial skill of logging in and switching users within multiuser targets, a key objective of the Red Hat Certified Systems Administrator (RHCSA) Exam200. This skill is fundamental for efficiently managing a Red Hat Enterprise Linux system, especially in multiuser environments.
Prerequisites Before we dive into the tutorial, ensure that you have:</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;red-hat-certified-systems-administrator-exam-objective-log-in-and-switch-users-in-multiuser-targets&#34;&gt;Red Hat Certified Systems Administrator Exam Objective: Log in and switch users in multiuser targets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the crucial skill of logging in and switching users within multiuser targets, a key objective of the Red Hat Certified Systems Administrator (RHCSA) Exam200. This skill is fundamental for efficiently managing a Red Hat Enterprise Linux system, especially in multiuser environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the tutorial, ensure that you have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Red Hat Enterprise Linux system (either a physical machine or a virtual machine).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valid credentials to log in to the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;logging-in&#34;&gt;Logging In&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-open-a-terminal&#34;&gt;Step 1: Open a Terminal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, open a terminal on your Red Hat system. You can do this by using the terminal emulator or pressing &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;Alt&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;T&lt;/code&gt; on the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-enter-login-credentials&#34;&gt;Step 2: Enter Login Credentials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the terminal is open, you will be prompted to log in. Enter your username and password when prompted. Ensure that you are aware of the correct credentials to successfully log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$ login: your_username
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$ password: your_password
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After entering the correct credentials, press &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; to log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;switching-users&#34;&gt;Switching Users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-use-the-su-command&#34;&gt;Step 3: Use the &lt;code&gt;su&lt;/code&gt; Command&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To switch users in a multiuser environment, the &lt;code&gt;su&lt;/code&gt; (switch user) command is your go-to tool. To switch to another user, type the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$ su - username
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replace &lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; with the name of the user to whom you want to switch. The &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; option ensures that the environment variables are set to those of the specified user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4-enter-user-password&#34;&gt;Step 4: Enter User Password&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After executing the &lt;code&gt;su&lt;/code&gt; command, you will be prompted to enter the password of the target user. Type the password and press &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;. If the password is correct, you will be switched to the specified user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Password: target_user_password
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exiting-user-session&#34;&gt;Exiting User Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-5-return-to-the-original-user&#34;&gt;Step 5: Return to the Original User&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To return to the original user, simply type the &lt;code&gt;exit&lt;/code&gt; command and press &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;. This will close the current user&amp;rsquo;s session and take you back to the previous user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$ exit
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastering the art of logging in and switching users in multiuser targets is essential for effective system administration on Red Hat Enterprise Linux. This skill will not only serve you well in the RHCSA Exam200 but also in real-world scenarios where efficient user management is critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have successfully learned how to log in, switch users, and exit user sessions, you are one step closer to becoming a Red Hat Certified Systems Administrator. Practice these commands on your system to solidify your understanding and enhance your system administration skills. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Remote Systems Using SSH</title>
      <link>http://b0x68.github.io/techcontent/access-remote-systems-using-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 09:31:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://b0x68.github.io/techcontent/access-remote-systems-using-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Accessing Remote Systems Using SSH In this tutorial, we will explore how to access remote systems using SSH (Secure Shell), a powerful tool commonly used in system administration tasks. SSH allows you to securely connect to a remote system over an encrypted connection, providing a secure means of accessing and managing remote machines.
Prerequisites Before we begin, ensure that you have:
A basic understanding of the command line interface. SSH installed on your local system.</description>
      <content>&lt;h3 id=&#34;accessing-remote-systems-using-ssh&#34;&gt;Accessing Remote Systems Using SSH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will explore how to access remote systems using SSH (Secure Shell), a powerful tool commonly used in system administration tasks. SSH allows you to securely connect to a remote system over an encrypted connection, providing a secure means of accessing and managing remote machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we begin, ensure that you have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A basic understanding of the command line interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH installed on your local system. Most Linux distributions come with SSH pre-installed. If not, you can install it using your package manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access credentials (username and password or SSH key) for the remote system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-1-open-terminal&#34;&gt;Step 1: Open Terminal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, open your terminal emulator. In Linux, you can typically find the terminal application in the Applications menu. On macOS, you can use the built-in Terminal application. If you&amp;rsquo;re using Windows, you can use software like PuTTY or the Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-2-initiate-ssh-connection&#34;&gt;Step 2: Initiate SSH Connection&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To initiate an SSH connection, you&amp;rsquo;ll use the &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; command followed by the username and hostname (or IP address) of the remote system. Here&amp;rsquo;s the basic syntax:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ssh username@hostname_or_ip
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replace &lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; with your username on the remote system and &lt;code&gt;hostname_or_ip&lt;/code&gt; with the hostname or IP address of the remote system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, to connect to a remote system with the username &lt;code&gt;user1&lt;/code&gt; and the hostname &lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt;, you would use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ssh user1@example.com
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If this is your first time connecting to the remote system, you may see a message asking you to confirm the authenticity of the host. Type &lt;code&gt;yes&lt;/code&gt; to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-3-authentication&#34;&gt;Step 3: Authentication&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, you&amp;rsquo;ll be prompted to enter your password or passphrase if you&amp;rsquo;re using SSH keys for authentication. Note that when typing your password, you won&amp;rsquo;t see any visual feedback (such as asterisks) for security reasons. Simply type your password and press Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the authentication is successful, you&amp;rsquo;ll be logged into the remote system via SSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-4-exiting-the-ssh-session&#34;&gt;Step 4: Exiting the SSH Session&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To exit the SSH session and return to your local system&amp;rsquo;s command line, simply type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;exit
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will terminate the SSH connection and return you to your local shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ve covered the basics of accessing remote systems using SSH. SSH is a powerful tool for securely managing remote machines and executing commands remotely. With practice, you&amp;rsquo;ll become comfortable using SSH for various system administration tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy remote system administration! 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
